Win and he lives to fight again. Lose and his family dies with him.
Triumph of the Spirit is a drama, war, history film directed by Robert M. Young.
During World War II, Salamo Arouch, a passionate boxer, is
arrested and sent to a concentration camp.
Soon, he is forced to box against his fellow
prisoners for the sake of entertainment.
Salamo Arouch, played by Willem Dafoe.
Gypsy, played by Edward James Olmos.
Father Arouch, played by Robert Loggia.
Allegra, played by Wendy Gazelle.
Elena, played by Kelly Wolf.
Avram, played by Costas Mandylor.
Triumph of the Spirit is a 1989 American
biographical drama film directed by Robert M.
Young and starring Willem Dafoe and Edward James Olmos.
The screenplay was inspired by true events, the same as the older
Slovak film The Boxer and Death directed by Peter Solan.
The majority of the film is set in the German POW camp at Auschwitz during the Holocaust and details how the Jewish Greek
boxer Salamo Arouch was forced to fight other internees to the death for the SS guards' entertainment.
The film explores themes of concentration camp, world war ii, jew
persecution, auschwitz-birkenau concentration camp, boxer.
The tone is emotional.